Finding Aid for Robert C. Metcalf papers, 1950-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert C. Metcalf papers 1950-2008, 1950-1999
Metcalf, Robert Clarence
4372 drawings
12 linear feet
2009179 Aa 2
Noted Michigan-based modern architect and former Professor and later Dean of the University of Michigan College of Architecture and Urban Planning. Metcalf's work includes over 150 buildings in Michigan and Ohio. The material in this collection spans the years 1950 to 2008, and includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, journals, articles, photographs and slides, client files, presentation boards, and architectural drawings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection was received from Robert C. Metcalf (donor no. 9920) starting in 2007. XXX
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert C. Metcalf was born November 7, 1923, in Nashville, Ohio. In 1940, Metcalf applied to the University of Michigan's Department of Architecture, writing in his application, "I would like to make a name for myself in architecture; rather, I am going to do that."[1] Metcalf entered the University of Michigan in the fall of 1941. However, on December 8th, the day after the Japanese attacks on Pearl Harbor, Metcalf and his friends took the bus to Detroit to enlist in the Marine Corps. Despite his eagerness to enlist, Metcalf was turned away from the Marines due to a punctured ear drum and flat feet. Returning to the university, Metcalf continued his studies until March 15, 1943 when he was inducted into the United States Army, where he was assigned to a self-propelled artillery unit for basic training. Metcalf completed his training on Memorial Day 1943, graduating with the rank of Sergeant, and four days later on May 28th married Bettie Jane Sponseller, a registered nurse from Canton, Ohio.
In August 1943, Metcalf was assigned to the Army Specialized Training Program (ASTP), a unit designed to provide the Army with highly trained technicians and specialists. Metcalf was sent to Johns Hopkins University for an intensive civil engineering program in which students completed the regular one year course of study in six months. In February 1944, the Army terminated ASTP and transferred its students to combat units. Metcalf joined the 84th Infantry Division and in September 1944 was sent to Europe. He served forty-two month in the Army with the 84th Infantry and was awarded the Silver Star medal and a field commission as a Lieutenant. After his discharge from the service in 1946, Metcalf returned to his studies at the University of Michigan.
While enrolled in the Department of Architecture, Metcalf began an apprenticeship with professor George B. Brigham, a practicing Ann Arbor architect. Metcalf was Brigham's chief draftsman on approximately thirty residential projects in the Ann Arbor vicinity, and worked for Brigham from 1948 to1952. Upon completion of his studies (B.Arch., 1950), Metcalf and his wife decided to remain in Ann Arbor. Demand for post-war housing was strong and Ann Arbor "seemed the best place to begin a practice based on contemporary house design."[2] To put down their roots, the Metcalfs found an available lot on the east side of Ann Arbor and decided to design and build their own home. Metcalf's rationale was that "with luck, the construction would attract a client, but in the worst case, we assumed we could sell the house to recover costs and then build another."[3] The design of the house took one year and the construction approximately thirteen months. Robert and Bettie each worked on varying aspects of the construction after leaving their regular day jobs, having picnic dinners on-site every night for almost two years. The Metcalf home was featured in the Michigan Alumnus (1961) and Better Homes and Gardens (1965). In 2008, the Metcalfs received a Historic Preservation award from the City of Ann Arbor for their home.
Metcalf's completion of his home coincided with the launching of a successful private practice. Bettie Metcalf retired from nursing in the same year to become the secretary and bookkeeper for Metcalf's new architectural firm. From 1953 to 2008, Metcalf's office completed over 150 projects in Michigan and Ohio. George Brigham's influence on the young architect was evident in Metcalf's modernist residences and commercial works. Metcalf's designs were also shaped by his esteem for architects Charles Sumner Greene, Henry Mather Greene, Bernard Maybeck, Frank Lloyd Wright, and Harwell Hamilton Harris.[4] Metcalf's work is notable for his emphasis on design analysis, a strength well reflected in his architectural drawings and sketches. As fellow architect and urban planer Gerald Crane observed, "Metcalf is the real thing. His work is totally honest and his construction drawings are absolutely meticulous."[5] Metcalf's houses reflect his beliefs in the importance of incorporating light, airiness, and nature into a home with the goal of creating "a serenity about a house."[6]
Metcalf designed houses and businesses for many of Detroit and Ann Arbor's most prominent citizens. Among the University of Michigan faculty and administration for whom Metcalf designed homes were physicist H. Richard Crane (1953), College of Architecture professor Catherine B. Heller (1953), chemistry professor Philip J. Elving (1954), physicist David M. Dennison (1954), anthropology professor Elman R. Service (1954), physics professors Lawrence W. Jones (1955) and Kent M. Terwilliger (1955), industrial management professor Franklin G. Moore (1955), internal medicine professor and Chief of the Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism Stefan S. Fajans (1957), professor of political science Everett S. Brown (1958), professor of surgery Dr. Reed O. Dingman (1959), engineering professor John Holland (1964) and professor of chemistry Lawrence S. Bartell (1988). In addition, Metcalf designed houses for Mr. Millard H. Pryor, Chairman of the Board of the Mollard-Barnes Manufacturing Company (1958), President of the Ford Motor Company Mr. Arjay Miller (1965), and Mr. George Huebner, a former Chrysler Director of Research, and his wife Trudy Huebner, a former University of Michigan Regent (1975).
Over the course of his career, Metcalf worked with other architects including Tivadar Balogh and William Werner. Tivadar Balogh, a fellow UM alumnus (class of 1952) and later instructor in Michigan's College of Architecture and Urban Planning, joined Metcalf's firm in 1954, working as one of his draftsmen until 1960, when he left to work as an architect and designer for the firms of Shreve, Walker, and Associates and W.B. Ford Design Associates, both of Detroit. Metcalf had a longstanding relationship with architect William Werner. Werner, some of whose work appears in this collection, joined Metcalf in professional practice in 1955. He received his bachelor's and master's of architecture from Michigan (class of '52 and '57, respectively), and taught structure courses in the College of Architecture and Urban Planning, beginning as an instructor in 1956 and retiring as a full Professor in 1998.
Among the many honors Metcalf has received for architecture are Honorable Mention in the Morton Arboretum Small House Competition (1954), an Honors Award from the Detroit Chapter of the American Institute of Architects for his own home (1955), an Award Citation from Progressive Architecture for designing the home of UM Professor David M. Dennison (1955), Honorable Mention with Tivadar Balogh in the Porcelain Enamel Design Competition for a youth center (1956), Third Award by the National Conference on Church Architecture for his work on the Church of the Good Shepherd (1958), the Homes for Better Living Honorable Mention from the American Institute of Architects, House & Home and Life magazines (1958), membership in the College of Fellows of the American Institute of Architects, and the President's Award for lifetime achievement from the American Institute of Architects (AIA) Michigan (1999). Metcalf also served as past president of the Huron Valley Chapter of the AIA.
Metcalf's work has been featured in numerous architectural journals including Progressive Architecture (January 1955), the Michigan Society of Architects' Monthly Bulletin (October 1955), Architectural Forum (March 1956), and the University of Michigan's College of Architecture and Urban Planning's Portico (1991). Metcalf has also received mention in other non-industry publications such as House and Home (1958), Ann Arbor Observer (1977), Ann Arbor Women's City Club Magazine (1982), Detroit Home (2004), Our House (2007), and Unwind Ann Arbor Business Review (2007). Stories on Metcalf and his work have also appeared repeatedly over the years in The Ann Arbor News, the Detroit Free Press and the Detroit Free Press Roto Magazine, the Michigan Alumnus, the Michigan Daily, Lansing's State Journal, and The Canton Repository.
In addition to Metcalf's private architectural practice, he had a long teaching and administrative career in the University of Michigan's College of Architecture and Design. He joined the Department of Architecture as a part-time visiting lecturer in 1950 and was later promoted to Assistant Professor (1958), Associate Professor (1963), and Professor (1968). In 1968, Metcalf was also appointed Chairman of the Department of Architecture. In 1974, the same year in which Department became the College of Architecture, Metcalf was awarded the University of Michigan's Sol King Award for Excellence in Teaching in Architecture. Metcalf served as the first Dean of the College, a position he held from 1974 until 1986. Metcalf stepped down from the Dean position in 1986 to begin phased retirement from the College. In 1989, the University of Michigan Board of Regents named Metcalf the Emil Lorch Professor of Architecture and Urban Planning. Metcalf retired from the university with emeritus status in 1991. Bettie J. Metcalf passed away in February 2008.
---------------------------------
Notes:
[1] Robert C. Metcalf quoted in "Retirement Memoir," University of Michigan Regents' Proceedings (May 1991): 226.
[2] "Metcalf Remembers," Portico, The College of Architecture and Urban Planning, University of Michigan (Summer 1991): 15.
[3] Robert C. Metcalf quoted in "Metcalf Remembers," Portico, The College of Architecture and Urban Planning, University of Michigan (Summer 1991): 15.
[4] Nancy Ruth Bartlett, More Than a Handsome Box: Education in Architecture at the University of Michigan, 1876-1986, (Ann Arbor, MI: The University of Michigan College of Architecture and Urban Planning, 1995), 107-108.
[5] Gerald Crane quoted in Ann Schriber, "Classy Styles: Well-known local architect's designs earn him admiration," The Ann Arbor News (30 May 1998): E1.
[6] Robert C. Metcalf quoted in "Metcalf built a rich mid-century design legacy," Ann Arbor Business Review (June 2007): 15.
Summary Contents List
Boxes:
Box 1 -- Project Files: Job Misc. 1950 Brechbuhler -- Job 14-55 King
Box 2 -- Project Files: Job 15-55 Phillips -- Job 35-57 Church of the Good Shepherd
Box 3 -- Project Files: Job 35-57 Church of the Good Shepherd (cont.) -- Job 50-59 St. Andrew's Church
Box 4 -- Project Files: Job 50-59 St. Andrew's Church (cont.) -- Job 77-62 Churchill
Box 5 -- Project Files: Job 78-62 Krigbaum -- Job 89-65 Courtland Corporation
Box 6 -- Project Files: Job 90-65 Miller -- Job 97-68 Towner Medical
Box 7 -- Project Files: Job 97-68 Towner Medical (cont.) -- Job 107-78 Claeys
Box 8 -- Project Files: Job 108-80 Watson/Akil -- Job 127-95 DeLosh
Box 9 -- Project Files: Job 128-96 Oak Valley Dental -- Job 149-05 Morshidi/Moazzami
Box 10 -- Project Files: Job 149-05 Morshidi/Moazzami (cont.)-- General Files: Newsletters
Box 11 -- General Files: News clippings -- Audio Visual Materials: Slides
Box 12 -- Audio Visual Materials: Slides (cont.)
Oversized Drawers:
Drawer 1 -- Drawings: Job Misc. 1950 Brechbuhler -- Job 8-55 Moore
Drawer 2 -- Drawings: Job 9-55 Jones -- Job 25-56 ICC Mark VIII House
Drawer 3 -- Drawings: Job 26-56 Woods -- Job 40-58 Campbell
Drawer 4 -- Drawings: Job 41-58 Titiev -- Job Misc. 1959 Furstenberg
Drawer 5 -- Drawings: Job 54-60 Emerick -- Job Misc. 1961 Likert
Drawer 6 -- Drawings: Job Misc. 1961 L. Price -- Job 83-64 Swartz
Drawer 7 -- Drawings: Job 84-64 Holland (I) -- Job 91-65 Hutt
Drawer 8 -- Drawings: Job 92-66 K. Siegel -- 103-71 Ecorse
Drawer 9 -- Drawings: Job Misc. 1971 Edwards -- Job 127-95 DeLosh
Drawer 10 -- Drawings: Job 128-95 Oak Valley Dental -- Job 150-07 Deromedi
Drawer 11 -- Presentation Boards: Job 0-52 Metcalf -- Job 24-56 Vaughn
Drawer 12 -- resentation Boards: Job 27-56 Patterson -- Job 35-57 Church of the Good Shepherd
Drawer 13 -- Presentation Boards: Job 42-58 Les Strang -- Job 84-64 Holland
Drawer 14 -- Presentation Boards: Job 86-64 Olds -- Job 94-66 Gilbert/Verbrugge
Drawer 15 -- Presentation Boards: Job 95-67 Metcalf -- Job 134-99 Holland
Alphabetical Index of Clients
Akil 8 see Watson
Alpha Delta Pi (Werner) 5 Misc 1962
Ann Arbor Airport 9 138-99 EAA (Experimental Aircraft Association)
Aris 10 (see Brigham files -- Wilcox)
Bagent 1 Misc 1951
Bareham 1995 9 145-03
Bareham 2003 9 145-03
Bartell 8 113-88
BBON Venture Medical Office 5 79-63
Bentley Park Shelter + Bandstand 7 98-68
Berkowitz 9 147-03
Bernstein 7 107-78 Claeys
Beth Israel Community Center 10
Beutler 4 63-60 Nao
Black 3 Misc 1957
Blackett 10
Bockenstedt 8 see Fox / Bockenstedt
Bookstein 6 Misc 1965
Botch 2 33-57 Franzblau
Brechbuhler 1 Misc 1950
Breed 4 67-61
Brown 3 43-58
Bull 1 Misc 1953
Busard 3 49-59
Cage+Smeckert Dental Office 5 80-63 Courtland Corporation
Campbell 3 40-58
Carr 3 47-59 Hurtado
Case 4 65-60 Stair
Chambers 10
Chatas (Werner) 6
Chen 4 51-59 Morshidi
Church of the Good Shepherd 2 35-57
Churchill 4 77-62
Claeys 7 107-78 Bernstein
Cohen 9 143-02 Woods; Siegel, Barry
Courtland Corporation 5 89-65 Cage + Smeckert Dental Office
Crane 1 1-53
Daniels 10
Darian 9 131-97 Mann
Davey 10 Paradise
Davidson / Sherwin 4 72-61
Client Name Client Folder Drawings: filed Cross-Reference Name(s)
on Folder in Box # under Job # for Same Building/Site
DeLosh 8 127-95
Dennison 1 4-54
Deromedi 10 150-07 (see Brigham files -- White)
Dingman 3 45-59
Divine Shepherd Luth. Church 10
Duckek I 2 23-56 Waggoner
Duckek II 4 74-62 Martin; Ragone
Dwight 10
EAA Project 9 see Ann Arbor Airport
Eaton 10
Eberbach 5 88-65 Malamud / Plotkin
Eckstein 2 21-56 Gerard
Ecorse Medical Office 7 103-71
Edwards 7 Misc 1971
Elementary School 10
Elliott 4 64-60 Hinman / Young
Elving 1 3-54
Emerick 4 54-60
Fajans 2 31-57
Ferrantino 6 see Williams, J
Ferriell 8 115-88
First Brethern Church - Canton 10
Forsythe 1 7-55
Fox / Bockenstedt 8 117-89
Franzblau 2 see 33-57 Botch Botch
Fuller (Hodges Travel) 4 71-61
Furstenberg (Brigham) 4 Misc 1959
Gamma Phi Beta 1 12-55
Gerard 2 21-56 Eckstein; (see Brigham files -- Baum)
Gilbert I 6 94-66 Gilbert / Verbrugge
Gilbert / Verbrugge I 6 94-66 Gilbert I
Gilbert / Verbrugge II 8 118-89
Gottlieb 2 32-57
Greenbaum 4 60-60
Greisinger also see Price, L; Vaughn
Grimord 3 48-59 Siegel, R
Grizzle 5 see McCauley / Grizzle
Gutstein 8 Misc 1992
Hall 4 Misc 1961
Hameedi 5 see 83-64 Swartz Swartz
Handy 10
Harris 10
Harvey 3 37-58 Mielke
Heller 1 Misc 1953
Heywood 5 81-63
Higgins 6 96-67
Hinman / Young 4 64-60 Elliott Elliott
Hitchman / Hewitt 9 139-01 (see Brigham files -Bailey)
Hodges 1 13-55
Holden 10
Holland I 5 84-64
Holland II 8 120-91
Hollinden see 27-56 Patterson Patterson
Hubbard 10
Huebner 7 106-75
Huron Valley Girl Scout Council 10
Hurtado 9 144-02 Carr
Hutt 6 91-65
Inter Coop Mark VIII House 2 25-56
Ireland 6 see 93-66 Swanson Swanson
Island Park Shelter 4 73-62
Jahnke 8 Misc 1992
Jones 1 9-55
Kienholz 8 111-85
King 1 14-55
Kleaveland 4 Misc 1960
Krigbaum 5 78-62
Kulitz 10
Kurkjian + Fisher 10
Laird I 5 82-63
Laird II 7 105-74
Leabo 5 87-65 McCauley / Grizzle
Les Strang 3 42-58
Lewis 6 Misc 1967
Likert 4 Misc 1961
Lingon 10
Loch Alpine Golf & Swim Club 10
Love (Report) 10
Lyon 2 29-57
Magee 2 28-57 McCoy /Steele; Nordman
Malamud / Plotkin 5 Eberbach
Malvin 10
Mann 5 85-64 Darian
Martin 4 see 74-62 Duckek II Duckek II; Ragone
Mayerson 7 102-71
McCauley / Grizzle 5 see 142-02 Leabo Leabo
McCoy / Steele 9 136-99 Magee; Nordman
Metcalf House Metcalf File Drawer
Metcalf Office 6 95-67
Michener 10
Mielke 3 Harvey
Miller 6 90-65
Moore 1 8-55 Seguino
Morshidi / Moazzami 9 & 10 149-05 Chen
Morton Arboretum Competition 10
Moyer 4 52-59 Yao
Mulchahey 4 59-60
Nao 4 see 63-60 Beutler Beutler
Newhouse 3 see 39-58 Pryor Pryor; Pleban
Nordman 2 see 28-57 Magee Magee; McCoy / Steele
Nu Sigma Nu 101-69
Oak Valley Dental Associates 9 128-96
Ogden 4 70-61
O’Hara 2 17-56
Olds 5 86-64 Valenstein
Owyang 9 Misc 2000
Paradise 2 19-56 Davey
Parry 4 58-60
Patterson 2 27-56 Hollinden
Paul 7 Misc 1974
Peter 3 46-59 Stein
Phillips 1 15-55
Phi Alpha Kappa (Werner) 5 Misc 1964
Phi Sigma Sigma 10
Planert 1 (see Brigham files -- Scharenberg)
Pleban 3 see 39-58 Pryor Pryor; Newhouse
Porcelain Enamel Competition 2
Potters Guild 10
Price, G. 10
Price, L. 4 Misc. 1961 also see Vaughn, Greisinger
Pryor 3 39-58 Newhouse; Pleban
Radock 5 Misc 1962
Ragone 4 see 74-62 Duckek II Duckek II; Martin
Reynolds 2 20-56
Richard 4 68-61
Riskey 2 30-57
Robinson 8 119-89
Root 4 75-62
Sahlins 3 36-57
St. Andrews United Church of Christ 3 50-59
St. Clare’s Episcopal Mission 10
St. Luke’s Lutheran Church 6 Misc 1966
Saladin 8 Misc 1993
Seguino 1 see 8-55 Moore Moore
Service 1 2-54
Shaffer 10
Shapiro 10
Sharp 10
Sherwin 4 see Davidson / Sherwin
Siegel, K 6 92-66 Yamada; Williams, J
Siegel, B 2 see 26-56 Woods Woods; Cohen
Siegel, R 3 see 48-59 Grimord Grimord
Spencer 4 69-61
Spindler 10
Sponseller 2 18-56
Spurr 4 Misc 1961
Stahl 10
Stair 4 Case
Steele 9 see McCoy / Steele
Stein 3 see 46-59 Peter Peter
Steiner 7 100-68
Stern 10
Stockon 1 5-54
Swanson 6 93-66 Ireland
Swartz 5 83-64 Hameedi
Tannenbaum 4 62-60
Terwilliger 1 11-55
Titiev 3 41-58
Towner Medical Office 6 97-68
Uete 10
UM Arch Bldg (Lorch Hall) 7 Misc 1971
Valenstein 5 see 86-64 Olds Olds
Van Boven 4 76-62
Vaughn 2 24-56 also see L Price, Greisinger
Verbrugge 6 see Gilbert /Verbrugge
VW Agency 2 16-55
Waggoner 2 see 23-56 Duckek I Duckek I
Warner (Werner) 5 & 7 Misc. 1974
Warren 1 Misc 1954
Watson 8 108-80
Weddige 10
Weid 2 34-57
Weinstein 10
West Park Shelter 3 44-58
Wilde 4 53-59
Wilkes 6 Misc 1967
William, B 1 6-54
Williams, J 6 see 92-66 Siegel
Williams, L.T. Missing - drawings lost in 1994 flood
Willits 3 38-57
Wollam - Restaurant 1 10-55
Woods 2 26-56 Cohen; Siegel, B
Yamada 6 Siegel; Williams, J
Yao 8 121-91 Moyer
Young 4 see Hinman / Young
The Robert C. Metcalf papers include architectural drawings, presentation boards, client files, photographs, slides, and negatives of Metcalf's work on residential, commercial, and community projects. The collection provides comprehensive documentation on virtually all of the projects undertaken by Metcalf. Projects are documented from design to construction and often subsequent additions and renovations. The materials in the collection are organized into three series: Project Files, General Files, and Audio Visual Materials.
Subjects:
Architects--United States.; Architecture--Designs and plans.; Architecture--Michigan.; Architecture--Ohio.; Architecture, Domestic.; Modern movement (Architecture); Balogh, Tivadar.; Brigham, George Bickford, 1889-; Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Elving, Philip Juliber, 1913-; Huebner, Gertrude, 1915-; Jones, Lawrence W. (Lawrence William), 1925-; Metcalf, Robert Clarence, 1923-; Werner, William A.; University of Michigan. College of Architecture and Design.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Architects--United States.; Architecture--Designs and plans.; Architecture--Michigan.; Architecture--Ohio.; Architecture, Domestic.; Modern movement (Architecture); Balogh, Tivadar.; Brigham, George Bickford, 1889-; Dennison, David M. (David Mathias), 1900-1976.; Elving, Philip Juliber, 1913-; Huebner, Gertrude, 1915-; Jones, Lawrence W. (Lawrence William), 1925-; Werner, William A.
Genre Terms:
Architectural records.; Architectural drawings.; CD-ROMs.; Negatives (photographic); Photographs.; Slides (photographs)
- Project Files
  The Project Files series, 1950-2008, (10.5 linear feet and 4,372 drawings) comprises the core of the collection and consists of textual and visual materials related to Metcalf's architectural projects, including new buildings, renovations, and additions. The series is divided into two subseries: Projects by Job Number and Projects without Job Numbers.
  The Projects by Job Number subseries is organized chronologically by project number and year, and includes the client name and address of the building project. The material within this subseries typically include architectural drawings, as well as a client file containing client correspondence, design development materials, client specifications, and billing information. Metcalf's careful attention to detail is reflected superbly in the drawings in this collection. The description of the architectural drawings includes measurements for the individual drawings, medium (such as pencil on vellum or blueline print) and type of drawing (elevation, section, detail, etc.). Many of the client files also include real estate listings for the house that give a sense of its market valuation over time, as well as information on original and subsequent owners. In addition to the client file and architectural drawings, many projects also include graphic materials, photographs, slides, and presentation boards.
  Among the project files in this series are documents relating to the building, construction, and renovation of Robert and Bettie Metcalf's home in Ann Arbor. Of special note are two personal journals of "work done" that record the daily activities necessary to build the Metcalf house ca. 1952-1953. Hours were tallied for both Robert and Bettie and show the determination that they both had in building their own house. The journals reflect Robert's construction learning experience and are in his hand.
  The majority of Metcalf's project files consist of those with job numbers assigned by the architect. Metcalf labeled the client files, architectural drawings, presentation boards, and other materials with the job number. The job number reflects the project's sequence in the work done by Metcalf and his firm, combined with the year in which the project was contracted. For instance, job 2-54 is the second job of Metcalf's professional practice and was commissioned in 1954. In addition to job numbers, Metcalf also referred to projects by the client's surname. Although the majority of Metcalf's projects are organized by job number, there is also an index of jobs by surname following the Processing Note in this finding aid.
  The Projects without Job Numbers subseries is organized alphabetically by client last name. The files within this series consist of information on clients, but do not include architectural drawings or other project-related materials.
  - Projects by Job Number
    - Job No. Misc. 1950 Mr. and Mrs. Clyde Brechbuhler, 4th Street, SE., North Industry, OH, 1950
      (not built)
      - Architectural Drawings, 1 17x11, 6 24x18, 1 25.5x20.5, 1 27x21, & 14 35x22-inch drawings; blueline, blueprint, pencil on vellum; plans, elevations, sections, details (Map-case 1)
        (oversized)
      - Client file (Box 1)
      - Slides (Box 12)
        (slide box 1)
    - Job No. Misc. 1951 Mr. and Mrs. HK Bagent, North Industry, OH, 1951
      - Architectural Drawings, 10 30x20-inch drawings; pencil on vellum; plans, elevations, sections, details (Map-case 1)
      - Client file (Box 1)
    - Job 0-52, Mr. and Mrs. Robert C. Metcalf 1052 Arlington Boulevard, Ann Arbor, MI, 1952
      - Construction Journals, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Graphics File (Box 1)